Julio Noriega

Chief Strategy and Business Development Officer Grupo El Comercio

jnoriega@comercio.com.pe

Summary

A senior business leader with over 20 years experience directing multinational companies and/or business units, with a solid foundation in board of directors, executive committees and general management positions with direct responsibility for corporate strategy, business development and P&L results.

Strong emphasis in corporate governance, organizational structuring, strategic planning, financial management, business and commercial development, multiple distribution channels and international operations.

Expertise in deal origination, company valuation, financial modeling, complex negotiations, capital structuring, and executing due diligence, purchase and share holders agreements and integration processes for mergers & acquisitions, as well as company restructuring, turn around and optimization.

Proficiency in leading road shows before principal global private equity firms and external consulting teams.

Accomplished in developing and implementing projects, launching brands or products, increasing sales and operational efficiencies in core business units while identifying and pursuing new sources of revenues. Skillfull in managing multiple distribution platforms, consumer services, packaged goods, retail and digital (internet & mobile) channels.

Focused in creating a company culture to facilitate innovation and collaboration. Vigorous about communicating clearly and inspiring team members. Concentrated in generating a company vision that attracts talent and mobilizes team leaders. Passionate about embedding the brand positioning into the operational excellence to deliver the value proposal and experience to clients.

Fervent about planning and prioritizing. Passionate about building industry expertise through advisory and working side by side and bottom up with executive teams.

Diligent and principled.

Experience

Chief Strategy and Business Development Officer at Grupo El Comercio (Multimedia)

May 2008 - Present

Strategic Planning & Portfolio Management

Business Development, Restructuring & Supervision

Private Equity, Mergers and Acquisitions, Buy & Build, Start Up Investments

Innovation & Digital Media Strategy & Partnerships

Director Coney Park, Happy City, Yukids (100+ Malls, 140 stores, 60,000 m2- Peru, Colombia, Chile)

Director Avansys Technological Superior Institute (6,000 students)

General Manager Peru.com

Board of Director and Executive Committee Member

2013 - Present

Acquisition, operation and expansion of educational technical institutes (Avansys)

Board of Director and Executive Committee Member

2013 - Present

Acquisition, operation and expansion of family entertainment centers - Coney Park, HappyCity & Yukids / 100 Malls, 140 Stores, 60,000 m2 / Peru, Colombia & Chile

Corporate Investment Committee Member

2012 - Present

Mergers and Acquisition, Buy and Build and Start Up Investments Portfolio Management and Growth Strategy

Digital Committee Member

2012 - Present

Corporate Digital Strategy

Vice President at Venevision International - Cisneros Group of Companies

January 2001 - May 2008 (7 years 5 months)

Mutltimedia and entertainment management and business development

General Manager at 20th Century Fox

1995 - 1999 (5 years)

General Manager at Warner Bros. Entertainment Group of Companies

1991 - 1999 (9 years)

Education

University of Pennsylvania - The Wharton School

Corporate Finance - Executive Education, Accounting and Finance, 1997 - 1997

Harvard University

Complex Negotiations, Comprehensive Leadership Program, 1997 - 1997

Northwestern University - Kellogg School of Management

Business Marketing Strategy, Executive Program, Marketing and Sales, 1998 - 1998

Price Waterhouse Coopers Executive Program

Mergers and Acquisitions, 2008 - 2008

San Diego State University-California State University

Finance, General Administration, 1985 - 1990

Colegio Santa Maria

Julio Noriega

Chief Strategy and Business Development Officer Grupo El Comercio

jnoriega@comercio.com.pe



Contact Julio on LinkedIn